usaepay.info 2016-06-11

# Privacy Policy - USAePay

**Scope of This Policy – Effective 02/28/2014**

This Privacy Policy covers USAePay’s treatment of personally identifiable information collected from merchants (hereafter “merchant” or “you”) who use the USAePay payment gateway services, as well as consumer information that we acquire in the course of our business. This Policy also covers the treatment of personally identifiable information that USAePay’s business partners may share with it.

This Policy does not apply to the practices of companies that USAePay does not own or control, or to people that USAePay does not employ or manage. USAePay is a wholly owned subsidiary of GorCorp, Inc. This Policy is specific to USAePay and does not apply to other Web sites or Internet services that are part of GorCorp, Inc.

USAePay has been awarded TRUSTe’s Privacy Seal signifying that TRUSTe has reviewed this privacy policy and practices for compliance with [TRUSTe’s program requirements](http://www.truste.com/privacy-program-requirements) including transparency, accountability and choice regarding the collection and use of your personally identifiable information.  The TRUSTe program does not cover information that is collected through this Web site, www.usaepay.com.

TRUSTe’s mission, as an independent third party, is to accelerate online trust among consumers and organizations globally through its leading privacy trustmark and innovative trust solutions. If you have questions or complaints regarding our privacy policy or practices, please contact us at 866-872-3729 or info@usaepay.com.  If you are not satisfied with our response you can contact [TRUSTe here](http://watchdog.truste.com/pvr.php?page=complaint).

 **Information Collection and Use**

USAePay collects personally identifiable information when you register for USAePay account, and when you use certain USAePay products and services. USAePay may also receive personally identifiable information from its resellers and other business partners.

When you register with USAePay, we ask for your contact information (such as your name, street address and email address), as well as certain information pertaining to your business, along with billing information such as a bank account and/or credit card number.

In the course of processing a payment transaction, we typically receive information related to the transaction from the merchant or a financial institution. This normally includes information about the payment that a consumer has furnished to the merchant or financial institution in the course of placing the order. We do not acquire any information directly from consumers through the www.usaepay.com Web site. We do not sell your personally identifiable  information to third parties.

The personally identifiable information we acquire in processing payment transactions varies according to the nature of the transaction and the way in which merchants or financial institutions are using our payment services. It may include, for example, the amount of the transaction, the consumer’s name, credit card number and expiration date or checking account number, billing address, and shipping address.

USAePay uses the information collected to fulfill your requests for products and/or services, to process payment transactions, to facilitate billing, and otherwise deliver the payment gateway services. Personally identifiable consumer information is only used to process payment transactions and is never used for any other purpose.

USAePay does not offer services or sell products to children. USAePay does not request or knowingly collect personally identifiable contact information from anyone under the age of 13.

 **Information Sharing and Disclosure**

Protecting personally identifiable information about merchants and consumers is an important part of our business. We share and disclose such information only as described below.

USAePay will only send personally identifiable information about you to other companies or people when: 1) we have your consent to share the information; 2) we need to share your information to provide the product or service you have requested; 3) we need to send the information to companies who work on behalf of USAePay to provide a product or service to you (unless we tell you differently these companies do not have any right to use the personally identifiable information we provide them beyond what is necessary to assist us).

Personally identifiable consumer information is shared with third parties (such as banks and credit card processors) to the extent necessary for USAePay to deliver payment-processing services.

We also may release personally identifiable information when we believe release is appropriate to comply with law, such as a subpoena, or similar legal process; enforce or apply our Merchant Agreement and other agreements; or protect the rights, property, or safety of USAePay, our users, or others. This includes exchanging information with other companies and organizations for fraud protection and risk reduction.

In the unlikely event that USAePay is acquired, merchant account information may be one of the transferred assets. We will notify our merchants via email and/or via a prominent notice on our Web site of any change in ownership or uses of your personally identifiable information, as well as any choices you may have regarding your personally identifiable information

 **Information Security**

Information security is critical to our business. We work to protect the security of your information during transmission by using Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) software, which encrypts the information you input. We store information gathered on secure computers located in a locked data center. The number of employees involved in the management of the data center that have physical access to these computers is limited. We use firewalls and other security technology to prevent our computers from being accessed by unauthorized persons.

We also require that all personally identifiable consumer information sent to us by you be encrypted using SSL encryption.

It is important for you to protect against unauthorized access to your Login ID/password and to your computer. Be sure to sign off when finished using a shared computer and otherwise protect the password used to access USAePay services. No method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure, however. Therefore, we cannot guarantee its absolute security. If you have any questions about security on our Web site, you can contact us at support@usaepay.com.

 **Cookies**

We may use cookies, for example, to keep track of your preferences and profile information. Cookies are also used to collect general usage and volume statistical information that does not include personally identifiable information.

We use another company to place cookies on your computer to collect non-personally identifiable information to compile aggregated statistics for us about visitors to our site. The use of cookies by our partners, affiliates, tracking utility company, service providers is not covered by our privacy policy.  We do not have access or control over these cookies. Our partners, affiliates, tracking utility company, service providers use session ID and persistent cookies to make it easier for you to navigate our Web site, in order for you to use the shopping cart, etc.

 **Web beacons  **

Our Web pages contain electronic images known as Web beacons (sometimes called single-pixel gifs) and are used along with cookies to compile aggregated statistics to analyze how our site is used and may be used in some of our emails to let us know which emails and links have been opened by recipients. This allows us to gauge the effectiveness of our customer communications and marketing campaigns.

 **Account Information and Preferences**

USAePay gives you the ability to edit or delete your USAePay Account Information and preferences at any time by using the Settings option in your Merchant Console, or by emailing us at [support@usaepay.com](mailto:support@usaepay.com).

We will retain your information for as long as your account is active or as needed to provide you services. We will retain and use your information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements.

If you wish to subscribe to our newsletter(s), we will use your name and email address to send the newsletter to you. Out of respect for your privacy, you may choose to stop receiving our newsletter or marketing emails by following the unsubscribe instructions included in these emails, accessing the email preferences in your account settings page or you can contact us at [support@usaepay.com](mailto:support@usaepay.com).

 **Links to 3 rd Party Sites**

Our Web site includes links to other Web sites whose privacy practices may differ from those of USAePay. If you submit personally identifiable information to any of those sites, your information is governed by their privacy policies. We encourage you to carefully read the privacy policy of any Web site you visit.

 **Social Media Widgets**

Our Web site includes Social Media Features, such as the Facebook and Twitter button or interactive mini-programs that run on our Web site. These Features may collect your IP address, which page you are visiting on our Web site, and may set a cookie to enable the Feature to function properly. Social Media Features and Widgets are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our Web site. Your interactions with these Features are governed by the privacy policy of the company providing it.

 **Notice for European Users**

USAePay is located in the United States. Any information that you provide to USAePay will be transferred out of the EU to the United States. By providing personally identifiable information to us, you are consenting to its storage and use as described herein.

 **Changes to this Policy**

USAePay reserves the right to modify or amend this Privacy Policy at any time and for any reason. If there are material changes to this policy or in how USAePay will use personally identifiable information, USAePay will post notice on the USAePay news release page at www.usaepay.com prior to implementing the change. If you have additional questions about this Policy, please contact us at [support@usaepay.com](mailto:support@usaepay.com).

 **Contact Us**

If you have questions or concerns about this privacy policy, please contact us through the information below:

USAePay

1833 Victory Blvd.  
Glendale, CA 91201  
USA
